

# JEREMY ESPINOSA

### Web Developer

I'm a Web Developer with over 6+ years of experience looking for an opportunity to apply my programming skills. A self-motivated IT expert with extensive experience and understanding in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Reactjs, Nextjs, Nodejs, PHP, and mobile responsive web development, as well as excellent skills and abilities in developing clean and efficient code.

## **Personal Information**

Address:

866 Mahogany Lane, C. Dela Paz St. Caniogan Pasig City

Email:

jeremyespinosa1995@gmail.com

Contact:

+63 915 979 5830

**Education:** 

2012-2016

BS Computer Science, Technological Institute of the Philippines (TIP). Quezon City

**LinkedIn Account:** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremy-espinosa-213236119/

Portfolio Link:

https://jeremyespinosa.vercel.app/

Languages:

Filipino, English

# **Work Experiences**

August 2017 – Present

Music Tribe
Web Specialists

- Responsible for creating, improving, and developing websites using the best practices in coding.
- Provides support to current websites to enhance and clean up code for better performance.
- Creates automation project to avoid repetitive task of the company.
- Follows mobile first design and modular coding to have better code structure.
- Lead the front-end developer and set coding standards to follow.

June 2015 - July 2017

Gee Pacific Services Inc.

Web Developer

- Responsible for ensuring and maintaining the websites.
- Responsible for creating responsive websites for better usage in mobile devices.
- Responsible for utilizing Chinese CMS software in creating websites.

# **Projects**

#### **Music Tribe**

#### **C2C E-Commerce**

Lead Front-End Developer

- · Set coding standards for client-side code.
- Code review to maintain the quality of the code.
- Applied mobile first design to make it responsive to different sizes of devices.
- Applied pixel perfect for every page based on the mockup.
- Communicates with vendor to set correct API structure needed in client side.

#### Sales Forecast

Full Stack Developer

- Authentication using Third Party API.
- Implements Cronjob for importing new data based on scheduled date.
- Can export XLSX file with all the data.
- CRUD data.
- Can track the history who changed the data.
- Dynamic filtering means filter list depends on the current data.

#### Job Description/Pledge

Full Stack Developer

- Automating job description of the company's employee.
- CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) functionality.
- CRUD functionality varies in user role.
- Exporting of data to CSV file.
- Tracing user action to the application.

#### **Avatar Maker**

Full Stack Developer

- Automating the creation of the avatar.
- Creating avatar based on gender, position etc.
- Customizing avatar, you've chosen from top to bottom body parts.
- Storing of avatar, you've created.
- Search functionality to globally search another user created avatar.

#### **Business Card Generator**

Full Stack Developer

- Automated the creation of business card of employees.
- CRUD functionality of the system.
- Sending email to the admin for approving the created business card.
- Admin dashboard for updating the status of those business card created.
- Manage users who can access with admin rights.

#### **Digital Assets Management**

Full Stack Developer

- Manages digital assets of the company.
- Search through available assets to avoid duplication.
- Adding/Updating tags/keywords of the assets to search easily.
- Favorites assets to have collection.
- Can group download assets and compress it in zip file.

#### **MID Generator**

Full Stack Developer

- Automates the creation of the MID.
- List and filters all of the MID created of the user.
- Preview on how the PDF will look like when it's converted into a PDF.
- Can generate PDF.
- Can see the previous documents for reference for creating new MID.
- · CRUD functionality of the MID document.

# Tannoy, TC Electronic, TC Helicon, Lab Gruppen, Behringer, Midas Website

Front End Developer

- Supporting current and old websites.
- Improving coding structure using Modular Pattern Design.
- Handling data request to updates the downloads, software, and documents of the product.
- Creating new prototype of the current website for better experience for the user.

# Gee Pacific Technology Services Inc.

#### Superants.inc Website

Front-End Developer

- Created informational websites to know what company offers.
- Used Google Maps API.
- Created contact form to know users concerns.

#### Thesis

#### **GeoSCAN**

Mobile Developer

- Programmer and concept developer of the application.
- Assigned to acquire data from the Police station of the target location of this app.
- Assigned to utilize the Google Maps API to provide the functionality needed by the application.

# **Skills**

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS (LESS/SCSS), BEM, CSS Module, Mobile First Design
- Bootstrap 3/4/5
- JavaScript (Object Notation Design Pattern)
- iQuery
- Reactjs, Nextjs, Redux, React Bootstrap, Nodejs
- PHP, MySQL
- CodeIgniter MVC Framework

# **Tools**

- Tortoise SVN, Git, Source Tree
- JS Task Runner (Gulp, Grunt)
- NPM, NVM
- Jira, Wrike
- FileZilla
- Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text
- HeidiSQL, SQLYog

## **Certifications and Awards**

- Certificate of Recognition for being on the Dean's List for the First Semester, School Year 2013-2014.
- Certificate of Recognition for being on the Dean's List for the First Semester, School Year 2015-2016.
- Certificate of Recognition for being on the VPAA's List for the Second Semester, School Year 2015-2016
- Certificate of Recognition for winning 3<sup>rd</sup> place in the Science and Technology Fair 2016 during TIP's 54<sup>th</sup> Foundation Anniversary